Finding Aid for William P. Favorite Papers, 1918-1977
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
William P. Favorite Papers 1918-1977
Favorite, William P. (William Perrin), 1898-1992.
0.75 linear ft.
88299 Aa 2
Graduate of the College of Engineering of the University of Michigan, later founder of Radio Construction Company, firm that erected various radio towers, notably the University of Michigan's Peach Mountain Radio Astronomy Observatory. Files relating to his construction business and to University of Michigan reunions; also collected materials relating to the history of Sturgis, Michigan.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Mrs. Victoria Favorite (donor no. 7464 ) and came to the library on July 23, 1987.
The collection is open to research.
William P. Favorite was a graduate in chemical engineering at the University of Michigan, class of 1920.
The William P. Favorite collection contains material relating to reunions of the 1917 and 1920 graduating classes of the School of Engineering at the University of Michigan; records, 1941-1962, of Radio Construction Company, including material related to the construction of the University of Michigan's Peach Mountain Radio Astronomy Observatory; and collected material relating to the history of Favorite's home town of Sturgis, Michigan.
Subjects:
Astronomical observatories.; Favorite, William P. (William Perrin), 1898-1982.; Radio broadcasting--United States.; Radio Construction Company (Detroit, Mich.); Peach Mountain Radio Astronomy Observatory (Mich.); Sturgis (Mich.); Towers.; University of Michigan--Alumni and alumnae.; Willow Run bomber plant.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Bridges.; Broadcasting.; Detroit (Mich.)--Streets.; Favorite, William P. (William Perrin), 1898-1982.; Fort Street (Detroit, Mich.)--1931-1940.; Jefferson Avenue (Detroit, Mich.)--1939.; Signal towers.; Streets--Michigan--Detroit.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Class Reunions, 1940-1977
  - University of Michigan, 1917 Engineering-60 year reunion, 1977 (Box 1)
  - University of Michigan, 1920 Engineering-20 year reunion, 1940 (Box 1)
  - University of Michigan, 1920 Engineering-40, 45, and 50 year reunions, 1960, 1965 and 1970 (Box 1)
- Radio Construction Company, 1941-1962
  - Articles of incorporation and business records, 1941-1944 (Box 1)
  - Ford Motor Company-Willow Run Bomber Plant, 1941-1942 (Box 1)
  - General, 1947-1962 (Box 1)
  - Photographs of radio towers and of Detroit streets and landmarks (Box 1)
  - University of Michigan Peach Mountain Radio Astronomy Observatory, 1957-1962 (Box 1)
  - WLDM Radio, Detroit, 1947-1948, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - WXYZ Radio, Detroit, 1941 (Box 1)
- Other papers
  - Sturgis, Michigan, 2 notebooks now in folders (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1918, 1950 (Box 1)